SHYAMALI NANDANWAR



shyamali.nandanwar@gmail.com



+91 9890955171



https://www.linkedin.com/in/shyamalin



(https://github.com/ShyamaliNandanwar

EDUCATION

SHRI RAMDEOBABA COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING AND MANAGEMENT, NAGPUR, MAHARASHTRA,

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Science and Engineering (Jul, 2014 – May, 2018) GPA: 9.06

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming: Java, JavaScript, PL/SQL, HTML, Angular JS.
- Databases: Oracle DB, IBM DB2, Sybase
- Familiarity with Python, JQuery, Spring Boot, Java Spark, Shell Scripting, React, Typescript.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Rookie Award (Division Level) Morgan Stanley India Circle of Excellence Awards, 21
- Debut Talent Award Morgan Stanley IST Quarterly Recognition Awards, 21
- Achieved All India Rank of 404 in Open Coding Contest of Code Gladiators, 17

PUBLICATION

Ramchandani, D., Alla, V., Nandanwar, S. and Hira, S. "An Ensemble Approach to Identify Hindi Speech Emotions." Journal of Advanced Research in Dynamical and Control Systems Vol. 11(No.5) (2019): 553-576.

VOLUNTEERING

- Participated in newspaper bag making for local shop owners
- Participated in Oracle Volunteering events.
- Ed-support Volunteer at Make A Difference (Non-profit Organization), Nagpur (Aug, 2015 – Mar, 2016)

INTERESTS

Reading, Painting, Sketching, Calligraphy.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A dedicated and self-motivated individual with over 4+ years of experience in the field of Software Development, frontend and backend both. Familiar with wide range of programming languages and keen on taking up new opportunities. Ability to communicate effectively and a good team player.

WORK HISTORY

Senior Manager | Morgan Stanley Advantage Services Private Limited | Bangalore, Karnataka, IN

December, 2020 - Present

Working as a Developer in CVA (Credit Valuation Adjustment) team, which is responsible for calculating the potential credit risk for the firm.

- Built a multi-threaded rest client to fetch data from an upstream system. Also worked with subscriber app for CPS service, learnt about how pub-sub mechanism works. Also, got a good hands-on on spark framework.
- Successfully delivered changes that helped in improving pricing efficiency for a certain category of trades. In addition, worked on various enhancements in business logic and dependencies that have helped in optimising the timings for various processes/jobs.
- Mentored interns and new grads, also conducted KT sessions, and performed code reviews.
- Worked on migrating legacy set up to align with new system setup for certain products which helps in finishing batch early.
- Established a setup that creates alerts for market data when a threshold breach is observed. This helps in detecting scenarios for suspicious-looking data beforehand.
- Renovated an internal monitoring website into HTML/JS from Java Servlets, used by mainly Operations and QA team, to monitor the arrival of data from various upstreams. Also, added multiple functionalities under same website, which previously were different webpages, reducing to and fro for a user.

Staff Consultant | Oracle Financial Services Software | Bangalore, Karnataka, IN

September, 2018 – December, 2020

Worked on customizations based on client requirements for the Oracle Banking Application called Flexcube. Technologies involved were PL/SQL and JavaScript for backend logic and Rapid Application Development (RAD) tool for developing front-end screens.

Web Developer Intern | Flying Penguins | Nagpur, Maharashtra, IN May, 2017 – July, 2017

Worked mainly on front-end design and development using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Ionic 3, Angular JS, and MongoDB. Developed UI components for the cross-platform app in food domain.